nmt.edu 2019-11-27

# NMT Privacy Policy: New Mexico Tech

New Mexico Tech maintains its web sites as an information resource and service for the public and this privacy policy applies to all pages of this site that are maintained by New Mexico Tech (https://www.nmt.edu) Our policy is to collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to make such information available to us. 

### Personally Identifiable Information

If you send us an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, or fill out a form that provides us this information, we will only use the personally-identifiable information to respond to your request and analyze trends. We may redirect your message to another person who is in a better position to answer your question. Some departments include forms to be submitted in regard to acceptance into the school or their individual program and are reviewed by admittance committees. In regard to filling out forms, you will be given a chance to "opt out" of completing the form. 

### Google Analytics

New Mexico Tech uses Google Analytics to track and analyze internet visitor usage data, which may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type, internet service provider, the pages and files viewed on our site, operating system, length of visit, access times, referring website addresses, and web browser cookies. The information collected provides New Mexico Tech staff the ability to see which pages are most viewed and some aggregated data about users. This data is controlled under Google’s privacy policy; full text is available here: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/> . 

This non-personalized information is used to monitor site effectiveness and possible areas of improvement and is stored on Google’s servers. 

We additionally gather information regarding the volume and timing of access by collecting information on the date, time, and website pages accessed by visitors to https://www.nmt.edu. We collect this information to improve the content of our website, and no individual information is collected. 

Google Analytics is an industry standard. If for some reason you would like to limit the data shared with Google, it is suggested to use a private browsing window without being logged into any Google services. At the end of your session you should close the window. This will limit the information collected to only include your nmt.edu browsing behavior. 

Please visit the following pages for more information on Google Analytics terms of use and Google's privacy practices. To opt out of Google’s data collection, read more about the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. 

### Online Surveys

New Mexico Tech is a research institution. At any time, there are many online surveys being conducted. Unless otherwise noted on the specified survey, your answers are confidential and individual responses will not be shared with other parties unless required by the New Mexico Inspection of Public Records Act. Aggregate data from surveys may be shared with external third parties. 

### Links to External Websites

Webpages for New Mexico Tech and its academic and administrative departments may contain links to other websites. Outgoing links from New Mexico Tech webpages in no way implies authorization or endorsement of that site by New Mexico Tech, its leadership, or the New Mexico Tech Board of Regents. New Mexico Tech is not responsible for the content of these outside websites, or for their individual privacy policies. Readers are advised to carefully read and consider each website’s privacy policy before disclosing any personal information. 

### Social Media Policy

New Mexico Tech maintains social media accounts on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, and SnapChat. By following these accounts information may be collected by each social media company. Data collected by your use of these services is managed under those sites privacy policies. 

### Concerns or Changes

New Mexico Tech may change this privacy policy at any time by posting revisions to this website. Your use of this website constitutes acceptance of the provisions of this privacy policy and your continued usage after such changes are posted constitutes acceptance of each revised policy. 

Please check <https://www.nmt.edu/privacy> periodically for changes. If you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy or any revised privacy policy, please leave this website immediately. 

The authoritative source on this policy and responsibility for its implementation rests with the NMT Chief Information Officer. 

### FERPA and HIPAA Policies

NMT FERPA Policy

 NMT HIPAA Policy
